Register of the Chinese subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Chinese subject collection
1910-2003
XX745
Hoover Institution Archives
13 manuscript boxes, 1 cubic foot box, 4 oversize boxes, 3 oversize folders, 4 scrolls, 19 sound discs, 1 sound cassette, 10 microfilm reels (12.4 linear feet)
Reports, memoranda, correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, bulletins, messages, appeals, questionnaires, press releases, maps, silk embroidered portraits, memorabilia, and sound recordings relating to political, social, and economic conditions in China, especially during the period of the Civil War, and to the Tiananmen Square massacre of June 1989.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Reports, memoranda, correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, bulletins, messages, appeals, questionnaires, press releases, maps, silk embroidered portraits, memorabilia, and sound recordings relating to political, social, and economic conditions in China, especially during the period of the Civil War, and to the Tiananmen Square massacre of June 1989.
Art objects, Chinese.; Audiotapes.; China--History--20th century.; China--History--Civil War, 1945-1949.; China--History--Tiananmen Square Incident, 1989.; Sound recordings.
- Subject File, 1912-1989 (Boxes 1-4)
  Scope and Contents
  Comprised of maps, printed matter, and correspondence pertaining to Chinese history, arranged chronologically.
  - Miscellany, undated (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Photocopy of a brochure depicting the Astor Hotel in Tianjin where Herbert Hoover is said to have lived and worked.
  - General, undated, 1912-1952 (Box 1)
    Maps depicting sections of Szechwan and Hopeh provinces, as well as miscellaneous intelligence reports, pamphlets, clippings, bulletins, and notes relating to Japanese intervention in China, and to political, social, and economic conditions in China.
  - Consortium, 1912-1937 (Box 1)
    Correspondence and memoranda relating to the formation of a consortium of American, British, French, and Japanese banking groups to conduct commercial activities in China.
  - Sino-Japanese Conflict (1937-1945) (Box 4)
    Pamphlet relating to atrocities committed by the Japanese Army in Shanghai.
  - World War II, 1944 (Box 1)
    Composed of pro-Allied Chinese propaganda materials. Includes copies of four national anthems and one "international" song circulated by the Communists in Yenan.
  - Civil War, 1944-1947 (Box 2)
    Comprised of reports relating to economic reconstruction and cooperative movements in the border region area of China under communist control. Includes directives, agreements, and press releases relating to U.S. efforts to mediate between Nationalist and Communist forces.
  - Manchukuo, circa 1946 (Box 2)
    Typescript memoir of the granddaughter of Tsien Wei-hsia, the prime minister of Manchukuo.
  - Issue of China Press, 1946 June 17 (Box 3)
  - Nationalists, 1950 February (Box 3)
    Purported translation of a forged special friendship pact between the Chinese People's Republic and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics. First circulated among pro-Nationalist groups in Hong Kong.
  - Pamphlet, 1952 (Box 4)
    Issued by the Communist Party and relating to the role of Chinese workers in the industrialization of China.
  - Program and menu, 1956 (Box 4)
    Relating to the state visit of Chou En-lai to Burma.
  - Pamphlet, circa 1957 (Box 4)
    Relating to the gradual disappearance of free creative writing in Communist China.
  - Pamphlet, circa 1957 (Box 4)
    Relating to the bureaucracy in Communist China.
  - Issues of China Connection, 1987-1989 (Box 3)
  - Tiananmen Square Massacre (June 1989)
    - Appeals and questionnaires prepared by Amnesty International, undated (Box 3)
    - Electronic bulletin board messages, undated (Box 3)
    - Transcript of a taped personal account, undated (Box 3)
    - Booklets, 1989 June (Box 4)
      Relating to the ten-year reform movement.
- Memorabilia, 1949-1950, undated (Box 3)
  Includes a portfolio of Buddhist silk embroidered portraits, dating from the Chien-lung period of the Ch'ing dynasty, as well as two Nationalist Chinese flags.
- Audiovisual File, 1920-1953
  - Sound discs, 1949-1953 (Record cabinet)
    19 sound discs relating to Chinese revolutionary history, including mutual aid teams, policy towards marriage reforms, Sino-Soviet friendship, Mao Tse-tung, and Lu Hsun.
    - 1-2: Wang Kwei and Li Hsiang-Hsiang (dancing drama song)
    - 3-5: Huai Hai Battle Suite (popular song)
    - 6: We Workers Have Strength (popular song)
    - 6: The East is Red (North Shensi folk song)
    - 7: Praise to Leader Mao Tse-tung (North Shensi folk song)
    - 7: Support to Pla (North Shensi folk song)
    - 8: Glory to the Whole Family (Northeastern folk song)
    - 9: Learning of a Couple (popular song)
    - 9: Celebrate a Liberated New Year (popular song)
    - 10-11: Wang Hsiu-Luan (dancing drama song)
    - 12: Sweeping Wind and Peach Blossom Shop, Apricot Village (Kansu and Yunnan folk song)
    - 12: Shepherd's Song (Chingai folk song)
    - 13: Heroes Conquest Ta Tu River (fold song)
    - 14: Five Flowers Blooming (Northeastern folk song)
    - 14: Youth Join the Army (Northeastern folk song)
    - 15: Song of (popular song)
    - 15: Challenge of Production (popular song)
    - 16: Old Wang Ma Demands Peace (popular song)
    - 17: The New Moon Hangs in the Sky (Kangtin folk song)
    - 17: Shepherd Girl (popular song)
    - 18: Song of Miaos (folk song from Miaos)
    - 18: Sun Shines Red to Pomegranate (folk song from Miaos)
    - 19: Song of Erh Lang Shan (popular song)
  - Microfilm, 1920s-1940s (Reel 1-10)
    10 microfilm reels of documents pertaining to Chinese student workers in France.
    - College brochures, letters, postcards, and pamphlets, student applications, profiles, and pay rates, mainly in French, 1920s-1940s (Reel 1-5)
    - College brochures, letters, postcards, and pamphlets, student applications, profiles, and pay rates, mainly in Chinese, 1920s-1940s (Reel 6)
    - Documents, mainly in Chinese, 1920s-1940s (Reel 7-8)
    - Reçu de la Légation de Chine a Paris pour le couple de Comité Franco-Chinois de Patronage de Jeunes Chinois en France, 1921 (Reel 9-10)
- 2013 Incremental Materials, 1925-2003, undated (Map case, Boxes 5-12)
  Printed matter and optical discs, and oversize maps, arranged by format, then chronologically thereunder.
  - China Beyond Fifty, undated (Box 6)
  - The China Challenge in the 21st Century, undated (Box 6)
  - Hand Written Fundamentals of National Reconstruction by President Sun Yat-Sen 总理手书建国大纲, undated (Box 5)
  - I el pueblo vietnamia triunfara! I los argresores Yanquis Francasaran!, undated (Box 6)
  - In Memorial of Lady Jiang, Ms. Song Meiling 荣美遐龄 将夫人宋美龄女士纪念专辑, undated (Box 9)
    DVDs
  - The International Relations Theoretical Discourse in China: A Preliminary Analysis, undated (Box 6)
  - Jin Mao Tower VCD, 金茂大厦 VCD, undated (Box 6)
  - Memorials of Yu-Geng, Qing Dynasty, undated (Box 6)
  - Riji Gushi, undated (Box 9)
  - Russian-Harbin, Tubabao, Russian Shanghai, undated (Box 10)
    CD-ROMs
    Access
    Access copy exists for "Tubabao". Use reference ID xx745_0001_r2017.
  - Seminar on China-Singapore Suzhou Industrial Park, undated (Box 6)
  - Shanghai Hotels, undated (Box 10)
  - Street names and attractions of Shanghai, undated (Box 10)
  - Working papers in Asian Pacific Studies, undated (Box 6)
  - "The Killing of Shanghai People by the British and the Japanese," 英国日本之惨杀上海同胞, newspaper clipping, 1925 May 30 (Box 6)
  - "Why the Foreign Devil?,", 1925 August 15 (Box 6)
  - The North-China Herald and Supreme Court & Consular Gazette, 1931 (Box 11)
  - Maps of Shanghai, 1932, 1942 (Box 10)
  - Receipt, telegraph, pass book and others, 1936-1938 (Box 9)
  - Newspapers with pictures, 1937 (Box 10)
    Comprised of The Illustrated London News, The Shanghai Evening Post & Mercury, and Pacific Rim Focus.
  - Map of Harbin, 1938 (Box 11)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1940 (Box 10)
  - Shantan Bailie School, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Chairman Mao Tse-Tung's Important Talks with Guests from Asia, Africa, and Latin America, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Memorabilia, 1960, undated (Boxes 7-8)
    Includes coins, a sword made of coins, two fans, and a flag of the Revolution Rebellion Team: Beijing Bureau of Parks and Woods Yihe Garden, 革命造反队：北京市园林局颐和园, as well as a 1960s red flag of the People's Liberation Army General Staff Department and Political Department(高举党的总路线和毛泽东军事思想的红旗阔步前进（中国人民解放军总参谋部政治部 红旗 1960.
  - Latin America's Red Peril, 1961 (Box 9)
  - Journal of Cheng Pou, 正报, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Resolutely Struggle Against Imperialism and Neo-Colonialism and for the Economic Emancipation of the Afro-Asian Peoples, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Red Women's Detachment, 1966 (Box 6)
  - A Study on the Enlarged Propaganda of "The People's War," by the Chinese Communists and Our Counter-Measures, 1966 (Box 9)
  - Informes De China, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - An Outspoken Revelation, 1970 (Box 9)
  - China Weekly, 1971 January-April (Box 9)
  - China in Africa, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Chairman Mao's Theory of the Differentiation of the Three Worlds Is a Major Contribution to Marxism-Leninism, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Chairman Mao's Theory of the Differentiation of the Three Worlds Is a Major Contribution to Marxism-Leninsm, 1977 (Box 9)
  - All About Shanghai, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Communist China's Crimes in Drugging the World, 1983 (Box 9)
  - Shanghai: China's Most Dynamic, Cosmopolitan City, 1987 (Box 10)
  - Shanghai, 1988 (Box 10)
  - Shanghai: 1949 The End of an Era, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Peking and Harbin, 1992 (Box 12)
    Compact sound cassettes and CDs.
  - Latin American Studies, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - The Fourth, Fifth, Sixth Huang Hsing Foundation Distinguished Lecture in Asian Studies, 1997-1999 (Box 6)
  - Calendar from Russian Youth Committee, 1998 (Box 10)
  - The Carter Center Report on Chinese Elections, 1999-2000 (Box 6)
  - Russians in China, 1999-2002 (Box 10)
  - Chinese Holocaust, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Tibet Press Watch, 2000-2002 (Box 6)
  - China's WTO Accession: The Road to Implementation, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Dragon on Terrorism: Assessing China's Tactical Gains and Strategic Losses Post September 11, 2002 (Box 9)
  - San Francisco Freedom Forum, 湾区的清流, 2002 January (Box 6)
  - Tibet Press Watch, 2002-2003 (Box 9)
  - American-East Asian relations before and after Black September, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Chen Gong-bo (Kung-po Chen), 2003 (Box 9)
    Collection of papers, including a CD.
  - Chinese Communist Party maps (oversize), 中国共产党一九四九年以前出版之地图, before 1949 (Map case)
    - Brief Map of Situations in Central China; Hua zhong xing shi lue tu 华中形势略图 [n.p.], undated; 54x80 cm. (Map 3092/4514) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Detailed Map of North China; Hua bei ming xi di tu 华北明细地图 [延安], 延安印工合作社, undated; 77x102 cm. (Map 3081/7182) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Detailed Map of Situations in South China; Hua nan xing shi xiang tu 华南形势详图 [n.p.], undated; 45x61 cm. (Map 3101/4414) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Detailed Map of Situations in South China; Hua nan xing shi xiang tu 华南形势详图 [n.p.], undated; 51x64 cm. (Map 3101/4414a) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Full Map of China at War; Zhan shi zhong guo quan tu 战时中国全图 [n.p.], undated; 64x94 cm. (Map 3080/6656) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Maps of Base Areas; Ge gen ju di di tu 各根据地地图 [延安] 新华书店总店, undated; 48x63 cm. (Map 2991.1/5640) (Oversize folder 1)
    - New Picture of Nine Provinces in North-East China; Dong bei jiu sheng xin tu 东北九省新图 [延安], 延安印工合作社, undated; 65x55 cm. (Map 3082/7182) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Situation of Chinese Eighth Route Army and the New Fourth Army Fighting against Japan; Ba lu jun Xin si jun kang zhan xing shi tu, 八路军新四军抗战形势图, [n.p.], undated; 57x32 cm. (Map 2991.1/8630) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Traffic and Transportation Map of Shan Gan Ning Frontier Area; Shan gan ning bian qu jiao tong gan xian tu 陕甘宁边区交通干线图, undated (Oversize folder 2)
    - Zhou Peiqing Map of Beijing; Zhou Peiqing Beijing di tu 周培青北京地图, undated (Oversize folder 3)
    - Administrative Map of Jin Sui Frontier Area; Jin Sui bian qu xing zheng qu hua tu 晋绥边区行政区划图 [n.p.] 晋绥边区行政公署绘制, 1944; 86x54 cm. (Map 3081/1237) (Oversize folder 3)
    - Huaibei Area, Subei Area and E Yu Wan Frontier Area; Huai bei qu, Su bei qu, E Yu Wan bian qu 淮北区, 苏北区, 鄂豫皖边区 [延安, 新华书店, 1944] (中国敌后战场抗日民主根据地分区详图, 50x63 cm. (Map 2991.1/5602/no. 6) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Huainan, Suzhong, Wanzhong, Sunan, Zhedong Area; Huai nan qu, Su zhong qu, Wan zhong qu, Su nan qu, Zhe dong qu 淮南区, 苏中区, 皖中区, 苏南区, 浙东区 [延安, 新华书店, 1944] (中国敌后战场抗日民主根据地分区详图, 50x63 cm. (Map 2991.1/5602/no. 5) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Jin Cha Ji Frontier Area; Jin Cha Ji bian qu 晋察冀边区 [延安, 新华书店, 1944] (中国敌后战场抗日民主根据地分区詳图, 50x63 cm. (Map 2991.1/5602/no. 1) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Jin Ji Lu Yu Frontier Area; Jin Ji Lu Yu bian qu 晉冀鲁豫边区 [延安, 新华书店, 1944] (中国敌后战场抗日民主根据地分区詳图, 50x63 cm. (Map 2991.1/5602/no. 2) (Oversize folder 3)
    - Jin Sui Frontier Area; Jin Sui bian qu 晋绥边区 [延安, 新华书店, 1944] (中国敌后战场抗日民主根据地分区詳图, 50x63 cm. (Map 2991.1/5602/no. 4) (Oversize folder 3)
    - Map of KMT Armies Annihilating New Fourth Army Wan Nan Headquarter in 1941; Yi jiu si yi nian Guo min dang jun dui wei jian Xin si jun Wan nan jun bu yao tu 一九四一年国民党军队围歼新四军皖南军部要图 [n.p.] (In 皖南事变的真相), 1944; 42x37 cm. (Vault 4292.24/7904) (Oversize folder 1)
    - Map of KMT Armies Attacking Huang Qiao in 1940; Yi jiu si ling nian Guo min dang chun dui xiang wo Huang qiao jin gong yao tu 一九四零年国民党军队向我黄桥进攻要图 [n.p.] (In 皖南事变的真相), 1944; 34x28 cm. (Vault 4292.24/7904) (Oversize folder 1)
    - Map of KMT Attacks on New Fourth Army since 1944; Yi jiu si si nian yi lai Guo min dang xiang Xin si jun jin gong tai shi yao tu 一九四四年以来国民党向新四军进攻态势要图 [n.p.] (In 皖南事变的真相), 44x55 cm. (Vault 4292.24/7904) (Oversize folder 1)
    - Map of Three Armies of KMT Attack on New Fourth Army in Spring 1940; Yi jiu si ling nian chun ji Guo min dang san lu jin gong Xin si jun yao tu 一九四零年春季国民党三路进攻新四军要图 [n.p.] (In 皖南事变的真相), 1944; 27x38 cm. (Vault 4292.24/7904) (Oversize folder 1)
    - New Fourth Army Attacking on Enemies' Rear Area in Central China; Xin si jun jin jun Hua zhong di hou xing shi tu 新四军进军华中敌后形势图 [n.p.] (In 皖南事变的真相), 1944; 77x55 cm. (Vault 4292.24/7904) (Oversize folder 1)
    - Shandong Area; Shan dong qu 山东区 [延安, 新华书店, 1944] (中国敌后战场抗日民主根据地分区詳图, 50x63 cm. (Map 2991.1/5602/no. 3) (Oversize folder 3)
    - Full Map of West Pacific Ocean; Xi Tai ping yang quan tu 西太平洋全图 [n.p.] 新华书店晋西北分店发行, 1945; 79x55 cm. (Map 3970/1287) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Map of Chinese Coastal Areas; Zhong guo yan hai xing shi tu 中国沿海形势图 [延安], 延安印工合作社, 1945; 135x76cm. (Map 3080/7182) (Oversize folder 1)
    - Situation of Germany; De guo xing shi tu, 德国形势图, [n.p.] 抗战日报, 1945; 50x60 cm. (Map 3700/2614) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Administrative Map of Jin Cha Ji Frontier Area; Jin Cha Ji bian qu xing zheng qu hua tu 晉察冀边区行政区划图 [n.p.] 边区印刷局印制, 1946; 97x78 cm. (Map 3081/1313) (Oversize folder 2)
    - Detailed Map of Jin Ji Lu Yu Frontier Area; Jin Ji Lu Yu bian qu xiang tu 晉冀鲁豫边区詳图 [n.p.] 邯郸市教育出版社, 1946; 53x76 cm. (Map 3081/4604) (Oversize folder 2)
- 2014 Incremental Materials, 1910-1955
  Comprised of posters, cartoons, and leaflets, arranged by subject.
  - Anti-Japanese resistance and Manchuria, 1937-1951
    - "United Nations on the March," music and Chinese text, United Nations flag, undated (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - “Black Propaganda,” anti-Japanese propaganda, circa 1938 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Propaganda printed by American Forces in China, circa 1945 (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - Uncover Xiao Chunjin's Crime, undated (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - Anti-Japanese patriotic posters printed by Hunan University, undated (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - Materials issued by the Puppet Huabei Xinmin Hui during the Japanese occupation of China, 1938-1945 (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1945 (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - Newspaper clippings and personal letters of Martin Nosina, undated (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - Anti-Imperialism posters and calendar, undated (Box-folder 13: 9)
      Scope and Content
      Celebrating the 10 year Anniversaty of People's Republic of China.
    - Pro-Peking puppet government surrender leaflets, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 13: 10)
    - Korean War, UN Psychological Warfare in Korea, 1951 (Box-folder 13: 11)
    - Mixed leaflets, cards, and calendars, undated (Box-folder 13: 12)
    - Bookmarks, "How the Steel is Tempered," Luxun and Gorky, undated (Box-folder 13: 13)
    - Broadside slogans or pro-Nationalist demonstrations, 1947 March 18 (Box-folder 13: 14)
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA), 1932-1954
    - Xinmin newspaper, 1945 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Anti-Japanese, Anti-Jiang materials, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Shou., T. F., "The Korean Question," master thesis, Yanching University, 1946 (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Chongqing newspaper clippings on Japanese surrender, 1945 August (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - Occupied Tsingtao materials and charts, undated (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Christmas cards and Tianjin newspaper, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Recovery project of the Yellow river, Chongqing newspaper clippings, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 14: 7-8)
  - Chinese National Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (CNRRA), 1947, undated
    - Reports in Chinese, undated (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - "Survey of the Yellow River Project in China,", undated (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - "Serial Welfare Operations of CNRRA Regional Offices,", 1947 (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - CNRRA manuals speech, director Chiang T'sing-Fu, undated (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Miscellaneous materials, undated (Box-folder 15: 6-7)
    - "Organizational Law,", undated (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - "General Situation,", undated (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - "Problems within the Party" (Yu fei, Li lisan, Luo mai, Qu qiubai), Song from Longdong, undated (Box-folder 15: 15)
    - Introduction to TVA, undated (Box-folder 15: 16)
  - United States Information Service (USIS), 1946, undated
    - "The Battle of Berlin," USIS China SE Branch, undated (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - "How to Elect Good Land Tenant Commissioners,", undated (Box-folder 15: 10)
    - "American Army Out of China,", undated (Box-folder 15: 11)
      Includes a song with music notes, map of Singapore City, map of Xinjiang, Cambrian palaeogeography, and lithofacies of China.
    - Third plenary session material, undated (Box-folder 15: 12)
    - "Start Department Aid to Cultural Exchange with China," by Wellys R. Rech, undated (Box-folder 15: 13)
    - "America's New Policy towards Neighboring Countries,", 1946 (Box-folder 15: 14)
  - Chinese-American Joint Committee on Rural Reconstruction (JCRR), 1949-1955, undated
    - JCRR posters, publication, and other materials, undated (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - "Taiwan Agriculture Revival Program," propaganda materials, undated (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - Posters and pamphlets with English translations, 1955 (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - Public health posters, 1951 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - Taiwan agriculture and industry posters, undated (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - "Exhibition of Products of Oversea Chinese Industries," newspaper, 1954 (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - Agriculture technology posters, 1950 (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - JCRR leaflets on agricultural figures, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 16: 7)
    - Sino-American Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction, undated (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - Formosa (Taiwan), 1941-1952, undated
    - Nationalist Government Education Department, "List of Courses Offered by Chinese College of Agriculture, Engineering and Commerce,", 1947 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - Baili News, Central Daily News, 1952 (Box-folder 18: 8)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - Chinese Confucian Association circular to Herbert Hoover urging the U.S. to join war against Japan, 1941 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - Anti-CCP postcards, 1950 (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - Air raid precaution proclamation, 1951 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - Chinese government war savings bonds, 1944 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - Facsimile of Chinese checks and leaves from a Japanese book, undated (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - Comments on the North Atlantic Pact, 1949 (Box-folder 18: 7)
    - Translations, 1944-1945, 1952 (Box-folder 17: 8)
      Comprised of translations of J-6 in Japanese and Chinese, pass to summer palace, Travel Gazette, and anti-Japan leaflets.
    - Telescope Weekly, 1945 (Box-folder 17: 9)
      Comprised of a signature of Chen Shu Tang, Consul General of China to US in 1878, and an anti-Japan cartoon.
    - Materials on Tai-Ping Rebellion, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 17: 10)
      Composed of a namelist of Sino-American Research Society, and Jin-Ling University introductory leaflet.
  - The Platform of the Chinese Democratic Constitutional Party, undated (Box-folder 17: 11)
  - KMT materials, 1910-1951, undated
    - Leaflets dropped by the Chinese Nationalist Airforce on the mainland, 1950 (Box-folder 17: 14)
    - Leaflets dropped over the China Mainland on the eve of the Double-Ten Day, 1950 (Box-folder 17: 15)
    - Shih ping hua pao, No. 34, 1948 June 6 (Box-folder 17: 16)
      Illustrated sheet published by Ministry of National Defense.
    - Min chung, No. 2, 1947 May 15 (Box-folder 17: 17)
      Includes colored nationalist cartoons issued by Taiwan Provincial Government.
    - Kuo min chih shih. Nos. 66-67, 1947 September (Box-folder 17: 18)
      Includes sketches of Sinkiang and head of Chang Chih-chung.
    - Biographical analysis of the 6th KMT Central Executive Committee published by 書包簡訊社 in Yan'an, translated in Beijing, 1947 March 13 (Box-folder 17: 19-20)
      Includes biographical sketches of the 458 Central Executive Committee members.
    - Newspaper clippings, 1934-1951 (Box-folder 17: 21)
      天津英語雜誌 The Sentinel, September 1934;《孟姜女》音樂劇劇目 March 1946 上海 "Meng Jiang Nv" musical program; 第二戰區長官部音樂晚會節目單 Second war zone music performance for officers program, August 1944; 有關日本投降的重慶報章號外 News about the surrender of Japan; 《長城〉劇目 March 1946; 上海 "The Great Wall" program; 游台紀聞 The Great Safari, May 1951.
  - Chinese minor political parties, newspaper clippings, circa 1910s-1940s (Box-folder 17: 12)
  - The Manifesto - The Organization Principle of the Chinese Democratic Party, 1945 October 10 (Box-folder 17: 13)
  - Oversize materials, circa 1930s-1952
    - Poster and leaflets of the Chinese mainland Famine Relief Association, 1950 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - Posters on agriculture and public health, 1951 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - Posters and pamphlets on tuberculosis, undated (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - Hua Qiao Zhi Sheng, Voice of Chinese Overseas, anti-Japanese newspaper, undated (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - KMT 4th War-zone (SE China) Nationalist poster, "Support the War Effort,", circa 1930s (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - Forestry: Communist Forestry Program posters, 1952 (Box-folder 18: 6)
      Comprised of posters on hygiene and medicine.
- 2015 Incremental Materials, 1966-1976
  - DAZIBAO big character poster (大字报), 1966-1976 (Oversize scrolls 1-4)
    Historical Note